aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
That idiot is late!
저 바보, 이제서야 왔네
You still haven't changed for a time like this?
넌 이런 날까지…!
Sorry, sorry!
미안 미안
Sheesh...
정말…
Lian...
라이안…
When you came back, I was really happy.
네가 돌아와줬을 때, 나… 정말 기뻤어
This time, you will definitely find your race!
이번엔 꼭 검성의 동족을 찾아내라구
Thank you.
고맙다
-Gunkid!
-Yeah?
-건키드
-응
You gave me a lot trouble before, but you've grown up quite a bit.
네겐 엄청 애를 먹었는데 이제 의젓해졌구나
Got it? Become Lian's strength!
알겠지? 라이안의 힘이 되어 주라구
E- En... En...
에, 엔… 엔…
Yo- you idiot! Who'd cry on this happy day...
바, 바보 녀석! 이런 기쁜 날에 우는 녀석이…
Who would cry on such a day?!
우는 녀석이 어딨냐!
That's right.
그렇고말고
Today is the very first day of the new Sword Planet's reconstruction for Lian and Gunkid!
검성 재건을 향해 라이안과 건키드가 새로이 출발하는 날이야
Beautiful.
아름다워
I will never forget the beautiful scenery of this Earth.
이 아름다운 지구의 광경을 난 잊지 않을 거야
And...
그리고…
...its wonderful friends!
훌륭한 지구의 친구들도…!
Burn! En, the Brave of Flame
타올라라! 불꽃의 용자 엔
Super Life-form Genocide
Appears
초생명체 제노사이드
등장
They left.
가 버렸구만
It got somewhat lonely.
허전해지는군요
Are you also going to go back?
너도 돌아갈 거니?
Yes. As soon as I receive a new order from H. Q....
네… 본부에서 새로운 명령이 도착하는대로…
I see.
그렇군
Kai!
카이!
Say, Ms. Luna looks tired, so you should take her back!
자, 루나 씨 피곤해 보이고 하니까 바래다 주라구
M- Maria, I can do it myself...
마, 마리아…
나라면 혼자서…
It's fine, it's fine. Right, Kai?
괜찮아, 괜찮아
응? 카이
Oh, right. Luna has been injured, and...
아아, 그렇군 루나는 부상을 입었고, 게다가…
Don't say, 4 or 5!
Here!
자!
-Should we go?
-Ye- yes...
-가, 갈까?
-으, 응
Then, I'll go back to Dag Base.
그럼 전 다그 베이스로 돌아가겠습니다
I'll follow you for a while.
나도 중간까지 같이 갈게
What should we do? Should we go to the arcade?
어쩔까? 오락실에라도 갈래?
Hm, the arcade?
음… 오락실이라…
Sorry, En.
미안, 엔
I made a promise with Shin. Right, Shin?
난 신이랑 약속이 있어 그치, 신?
Promise?
약속?
Look at this!
이것 좀 보세요!
This rare clam should be assigned-
이 특이한 조개는 학명을…
You, follow me too!
너도 와야지!
Right?
그치?
No!
아니야!
Excuse me!
따라와!
H- hey! Wait! Wait a sec!
이, 이봐?!
잠깐, 잠깐 기다려!
What's wrong with him?
대체 왜저래?
I don't know...
글쎄…
Thank you.
고마워
Thank you for coming back safe and sound.
무사히 돌아와 줘서 고마워
Of course! I still have a debt to pay you...
당연하지 너한테 돈 빌린 것도 남아있고…
Oh, right! The debt!
그래, 빌린 돈!
The due date is tomorrow.
돈은 내일 갚기로 했잖아
Do you remember our promise?
약속, 기억하고 있어?
-Uh, yeah.
-Say it.
-으, 응
-말해봐
Quick!
얼른!
I guess I'll have to...
별 수 없구만
In front of the bank with a big clock nearby Sankai bridge at noon tomorrow.
내일12시 산카이 다리 옆의 큰 시계가 있는 은행 앞
Right?
맞지?
Don't forget the movie, meal, and karaoke!
점심 먹고 영화 보고 그리고 노래방도 잊으면 안돼!
Hey, you!
야…;;
Don't be late!
지각하면 안돼!
Sheesh...
나 참…
Energy reaction?
에너지 반응?
There's nothing.
아무것도 없잖아
My name is Genocide.
내 이름은 제노사이드
Genocide!?
제노사이드?!
What?!
아니?!
What the hell's going on?!
대체 어떻게 된 거야?!
Fire Jumbo!
파이어 점보?!
That time, that bastard said the following:
그 때, 녀석은 말했어
Genocide's objective is...
제노사이드의 목적은…
Fusing with the Earth.
지구와의 융합
Fusing?!
융합?!
I'll move to the Earth and born as a new planet.
지구라는 그릇에 옮겨 타 나는 새로운 별로 다시 태어날 것이다
No way... That's impossible!
말도 안돼…
어떻게 이런 일이!
My name is Genocide.
내 이름은 제노사이드
The absolute perfection.
절대적이며 완벽한 존재
Dammit!
젠장!
En!
엔---!
Genocide is fusing with the Earth!
지구와 제노사이드가 융합해갑니다!
It really is a super life-form!
저게 바로 초생명체!
Th- the Earth is...!
지, 지구가…!
Activate the Dag Light Wave Barrier!
다그 광파 배리어 전개 시작!
Rai!
라이!
Activating the Dag Light Wave Barrier!
다그 광파 배리어 전개!
Thankfully, this place is safe for now.
간신히 이곳만은 무사하군
What happened to the people outside?
바깥 쪽 사람들은 어떻게 됐을까요?
They probably would have been fused...
아마 융합해서…
It's a matter of time for us, too!
우리도 시간 문제예요!
We don't know how long the Dag Light Wave Barrier will hold!
다그 광파 배리어가 언제까지 견뎌낼지…
All resistance is futile.
이미 모든 저항은 무의미하다
Soon, you guys will be a part of me.
곧 너희들도 나의 일부가 되어
And I'll be completely fused with the Earth.
나는 지구와 완전히 하나가 될 것이다
At that moment, I'll be reborn as a new planet.
그 순간 나는 새로운 별로 다시 태어난다
What is it, Rai?
왜 그래, 라이?!
There are people!
사람이 있어요…
There are still people inside the Dag Light Wave Barrier!
다그 광파 배리어 안에 아직 사람이 남아있어요!
-What?!
-Alright!
-뭐라고?!
-좋았어!
Let's take them to the center of the barrier and take shelter!
그 사람들을 배리어 중앙으로 피난시키자!
We must split up and guide the school here.
분담해서 학교로 유도하자
Rai, you'll take care of Dag Base. This is the Earth's last fortress!
라이, 넌 다그 베이스를 맡아줘 이곳이 지구 최후의 요새야!
Yes, sir!
네!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Stop it! Help me!
그만둬! 살려줘!
Don't come!
오지마---!
I am the absolute perfection.
나야말로 절대적이며 완벽한 존재
I am...
나야말로…
the absolute...
절대적이며…
perfection...
완벽한 존재
I am...
나야말로…
the absolute perfection.
절대적이며 완벽한 존재
I am the absolute perfection.
나야말로 절대적이며 완벽한 존재
Ru- run away!
도, 도망쳐라!
To Sankai High School! Everyone, escape to Sankai High School!
산카이 고등학교로! 모두 산카이 고등학교로 도망쳐!
En!
엔!
Maria! You should hurry to the school too!
마리아! 너도 어서 학교로…!
What about you?
너는?
Just go!
어서 가…!
En!
엔-!
Be careful.
조심해…
Shield Smoke!
실드 스모크!
The opponents are human! Absolutely do not hurt them!
상대는 인간이야! 절대 다치게 해선 안돼!
We know!
알고 있다구!
Hurry to the school!
학교로 서두르세요!
Thank you, Dagwon!
-고마워, 다그온!
Futile.
소용없다
Everything on the Earth is in my hands.
지구상의 모든 것은 내 손 안에 있다
Dagwon!
다그온…!
Do not let it hit the building!
건물에 맞게 해선 안돼! 알았어!
The generator is... The barrier won't hold up at this rate!
제너레이터가…! 이대론 배리어가 못 버텨!
En!
엔…!
En, what will happen to us?
엔, 우리 어떻게 되는 거야?
Look up.
얼굴 들어
What will happen to the Earth?!
지구는 어떻게 되는 거야?!
Gaku!
가쿠!
You call yourself a Dagwon?!
네가 그러고도 다그온이야?!
I'm a... Dagwon?
내가… 다그온?
Dagwon means a brave person.
다그온이란 건 용기있는 사람을 뜻하는 말이야
Your courage has saved a small life!
너의 용기가 조그마한 생명을 구했잖아
I am a Dagwon too?
나도… 다그온?!
No matter how painful it is, never give up until the end.
비록 그게 아무리 괴롭다 할지라도 마지막까지 포기하지마
That is what a Dagwon is!
그게 다그온이야!
En...
엔…
Look with your eyes, Gaku.
잘 봐라, 가쿠
The last battle of Dagwon!
다그온 최후의 싸움을!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Fire En!
파이어 엔
En is... Dagwon?!
엔이… 다그온?!
Fire Stratus!
파이어 스투라투스!
What are you trying to do, En?!
뭘 하려는 거냐, 엔?!
You're going to be fused with Genocide!
제노사이드와 동화되고 만다구!
This is youth!
이게 바로 청춘이다!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어
Strength Fusion!
강력합체
(剛力合體)
Power Dagwon!
파워 다그온
How foolish.
어리석구나
Now, Rai!
지금이야, 라이!
Super Blazing Fusion!
초화염합체다!
Super Blazing Fusion?!
초화염합체?!
Quick, before the barrier breaks!
배리어가 부서지기 전에 서둘러!
B- but if you do that, you're going to be...
하, 하지만 그런 짓을 하면 선배가!
No time to think!
머리 굴릴 시간 없어!
Do your best, En!
힘내라, 엔--!
Rai, hurry up!
라이, 서둘러!
Understood.
알았습니다
I'll do it.
발사하겠습니다!
Super Blazing Fusion!
초화염합체
(超火炎合體)
Super Fire Dagwon!
슈퍼 파이어 다그온
I am the absolute perfec-
나야말로 절대적이며 완…
What are you doing?
무슨 짓이냐?
I will not let you do whatever you want to the Earth!
지구를 네 맘대로 하게 두진 않아!
Do you think you've won because of that?
그걸로 이겼다고 생각하나?
No!
아니!
From now on, you and I are one body and soul! The match begins right now!
나와 넌 지금 일심 동체! 승부는 지금부터다!
En!
엔!
It's futile.
소용없다
Taking control of your spirit is an easy job for me.
너의 마음을 지배하는 것 따윈 내게는 너무나도 쉬운 일이다
Shut up! I will not be taken over by the likes of you!
닥쳐라! 난 네놈 따위에게 지배당하지 않아!
Like hell I'm being controlled!
지배당할 성 싶으냐?!
You damn idiot!
어리석은 녀석!
Surrender and follow my orders.
순순히 내게 복종해라
And then I'll be born again into a new planet!
그리고 나는 새로운 별로 다시 태어날 것이다
Who will surrender to you?
누가 네놈 따위에게…
Do not defy me!
거역하지 말아라!
Do not defy me.
거역하지 마라
If you surrender, you'll be freed from that pain.
항복하면 넌 그 고통해서 해방된다
Kneel down before me!
내게 무릎꿇어라!
Never!
싫어-!
My spirit is... mine...!
내, 내 마음은… 내… 거라구…
It's not... of someone's...
그 누구의… 것도…
A human's youthful spirit is weak after all.
인간의 정신 따윈 결국 나약한 것
Now, clear your mind!
자, 너의 마음을 비워라!
Do not underestimate humans!
인간을 만만하게 보지 마라!
You're an inferior creature after all!
하등 생물 주제에…
Accept me!
날 받아들여라!
Never!
싫어!
You can become the ruler of the new planet!
넌 새로운 별의 지배자가 될 수 있단 말이다!
Don't make me laugh!
웃기지 마라!
Stop this!
그만둬------!
Stop this! You'll die too!
그만둬! 너도 죽고 말아!
That's what I wanted.
바라던 바다
What?
뭐야?
I'll...
네놈을…
I'll send you to hell!
네놈을 지옥으로 보내 주마!
No way!
말도 안돼!
I am the absolute perfection!
나야말로 절대적이며 완벽한 존재!
I am...
나는…
I am the absolute...
나야말로 절대적이며…
I am...
나는…
perfect...
완벽한…
being...!
존재란 말이다---!
I am... a Dagwon!
난 다그온이다---!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
kaze no naka no PRISM
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
-Principal, En isn't here.
-Daidouji isn't?
-교장 선생님, 엔이 없어요
-다이도우지가?
We promised to meet today, but he can't be found anywhere.
오늘 만나기로 약속했는데 어디에도 없어요
Tobe. If you promised, then please wait at the place you promised to meet.
토베 양 약속했다면 약속 장소에서 그를 기다려 주게
Daidouji is a man who keeps his word.
다이도우지는 약속을 지키는 남자라네
I understand. I'll wait for En.
알았습니다 저, 엔을 기다리겠어요
For him to come back...
그가 돌아오는 것을…
Yuusha Shirei Dagwon - the last episode! To Our Future...
용자지령 다그온 최종화
우리 미래로
To Our Future...